mobotix.com 2019-05-16

# Disclaimer and Data Protection | MOBOTIX AG

## MOBOTIX AG Privacy Policy dated 18 April 2019

### Disclaimer

Although we carefully check every link to pages of other Internet content providers, we will not assume responsibility for the contents of other websites. The contents of other content provider’s pages are the sole responsibility of these providers.

### Data Protection Statement

MOBOTIX AG take the protection of your data seriously. Our protection measures therefore closely follow the provisions of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) in their respective current version. Below we have outlined how we handle your personal data at MOBOTIX AG.

#### 1\. Protection Of Your Personal Data

Your personal data is stored by MOBOTIX AG on a server in the Federal Republic of Germany with state-of-the-art protection and is secured against unauthorized access. MOBOTIX AG employees are obligated to maintain confidentiality with regard to personal data.

MOBOTIX AG also provide registration forms on this website that can be used to register for training, events and the like. The input required for this purpose, such as address data, name and contact information of the person registering, is transferred internally by MOBOTIX to the persons responsible for processing and used solely for the intended purpose of processing the registration. The e-mail address and telephone number provided in this context are needed so you can be contacted in case of follow-up questions regarding your registration, and so that we can send you a reservation confirmation and further information about the events.

We have implemented a double opt-in procedure to prevent third parties from registering you for a newsletter via our homepage without your consent. We send an e-mail containing a link to the e-mail address you have specified. By clicking this link, you confirm that you agree to order the specified newsletter. Only then is your subscription active.

Wherever personal data is entered, the corresponding fields must be clicked to confirm that you recognize our Privacy Policy and have been notified of your statutory right to withdrawal according to the legal requirements of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG).

Without these two confirmations, the input of personal data and therefore the desired registration to a newsletter, event or the like cannot be completed.

MOBOTIX AG will not pass on your personal data to a third party at any time without your express consent, unless

a) passing on this information is necessary in order to implement offers or provide the services you wish to use,

b) a subcontractor which we employ within the framework of providing offers or services requires this data (subcontractors are only entitled to use data insofar as this is necessary for the provision of offers or services. MOBOTIX AG obligates its partners under contract to comply with data protection regulations),

c) an enforceable official or court order exists.

#### 2\. Collection Of General Information

The following information will be stored in a log file automatically when you access these webpages: date and time of access, IP address, link opened, information about web browser and operating system, volume of data transferred, error code and user name (in the case of customized access).

This data will also be generated when any other website is visited and is therefore not a special function of our website. Data is stored for security purposes and to improve our offering. This data is evaluated purely for statistical purposes in an anonymized form.

This data is deleted after 14 days.

#### 3\. Use Of Cookies And A Web Analysis Service

##### 3.1 Cookies

A cookie is a small text file containing information that enables the identification of recurring visitors to our website. Cookies will be stored on your computer. This makes it possible to adapt our website to your requirements (for example, language, country assignment) and to assign information to the session steps during a session.

Only the cookie on your computer is identified in order to ascertain whether your computer has already accessed our website.

Cookies also offer the option for you, as a user of customized services, not to have to register each time you make use of these. Personal data will not be generated or forwarded in any case, nor will a link to personal data be established.

The use of all our website’s functions requires cookies to be allowed during a session. Current browsers have a security setting which ensures that cookies are deleted automatically at the end of a session.

##### 3.2 Google Analytics

At MOBOTIX AG we take the protection of your personal data extremely seriously and abide by data protection legislation. Some of the data collected when you visit this website will be used for statistical analysis.

###### 3.2.1 Data Collected For Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies” – text files stored on your computer – for the purpose of analyzing the way you use the website. The information about your use of the website generated by the cookie is generally transferred to a Google server in the U.S., where it is stored. If IP anonymization is activated on this website, your IP address within member states of the European Union or other states in the European Economic Area is first shortened by Google. Only in exceptional cases is the full IP address transmitted to a Google server in the U.S. and shortened there. By order of the website operator, Google uses this information to evaluate your use of the website, compile reports about website activities and offer additional services to the website operator related to the use of the website and the Internet. The IP address transmitted by your browser within the framework of Google Analytics is not combined with other data by Google. You can prevent the storage of cookies by configuring the settings of your browser software accordingly. However, please note that it may not be possible to fully use all functions of this website in that case. You can also prevent the capture of data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) and the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>.

You can prevent capture by Google Analytics by clicking the following link. This sets an opt-out cookie that prevents the future capture of your data when you visit this website:

Deactivate Google Analytics

More information about terms of use and data protection is available at <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms> and <https://policies.google.com/?hl=en>. Please note that Google Analytics has been extended with the code “anonymizeIp” on this website to ensure the anonymized recording of IP addresses (IP masking).

##### 3.3 LinkedIn Insight Tag

The LinkedIn Insight tag allows to collect data about visits to the website from LinkedIN, including URL, referrer URL, IP address, device and browser properties, timestamps, and page views. These data are encrypted by LinkedIN, anonymised within seven days and the anonymized data is deleted within 90 days. LinkedIn does not share personally identifiable information with the owner of the website, but only provides aggregated reports about the website's audience and display performance. LinkedIn also provides web site visitor retargeting so that the owner of the website can use this data to display targeted advertising outside his or her website without the member being identified. LinkedIn members can control the use of their personal information for advertising purposes in their account settings.

#### 4\. Use Of Social Media Platforms

MOBOTIX AG not only make information available on their own website, but also on social media platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, LinkedIn and similar. Likes or similar may be assigned to pages or individual articles on these platforms. The input of personal data is not intended. Furthermore, MOBOTIX do not transmit or evaluate any personal information such as user-specific statistics.

#### 5\. Right To Information

Pursuant to Art. 15 GDPR and Section 34 BDSG, we will be happy to provide you with information about the data we have stored about you on request, including information about its origin and recipients and the purpose of storing this information.

#### 6\. Miscellaneous

MOBOTIX AG will need to adapt this Privacy Policy from time to time in consideration of applicable legal requirements regarding data protection. Always make sure that you have read the latest version.

If MOBOTIX AG commission partner companies to perform specific services, data protection regulations will be transferred to the contracts with these partners and the partners will be obligated to comply with data protection.

Your trust is important to us. We are therefore happy to answer any questions regarding the processing of your personal data at any time. If you have any questions that are not answered in this Privacy Policy or if you would like more information about a specific aspect, please contact our data protection officer at [data-protection@mobotix.com](mailto:data-protection@mobotix.com).

#### 7\. Customer Portal

Insofar as you use our customer portal, we store the data collected there for our own purposes and for dissemination to selected sales partners within the framework of the MOBOTIX partner program.

#### 8\. Right Of Withdrawal

You may withdraw your consent to the use of your personal data pursuant to Art. 7 (3) GDPR and Section 36 BDSG at any time with future effect. Further information about your right of withdrawal and its handling by MOBOTIX AG is found on the following page: https://www.mobotix.com/en/node/10078
